

CHRISTOPHER HARRIS

Digital Marketing & Web Development

PROFILE

For the past eleven years, I have aligned my education and professional skills toward creating user experiences that are inviting, empowering, and true to values espoused by the organizations for which I have worked. I am an experienced, detail-oriented communicator who enjoys working collaboratively to create intuitive, multi-channel user experiences that showcase the organization's value, drive audience acquisition, and increase engagement.

CONTACT

Address

832 Elgin Court Fort Collins, CO 80524

Phone

(505) 470-2054

Email

cHarris505@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charris505/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engagement Marketing Director

2022 - 2023

University of Colorado Boulder

- Managed a five-person team responsible for web, analytics, email, social, and project management
- Effectively managed twenty projects of varying complexity using Agile and Waterfall methodologies. Increased NPS by an average of 12.96% and event registration by 6.52%
- Identified key customer and market insights and implemented actionable strategies to improve marketing operations
- Defined analytics strategy and built dashboards in Looker to track alumni engagement across digital channels. Increased unique pageviews on the alumni website by 45.71% and engagements by 3.27%
- Developed scope and technical requirements for new DAM and project management tool integrations

Freelance Web Developer

2021 - Present

Cohesion Brewing Company

- Used agile project management techniques to build the brewery's <u>custom website</u> using HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Developed UI/UX and responsive layout for seven landing pages and Cohesion's digital store. Since launch, the website has received 73,034 unique visitors and generated roughly \$6,100 in sales
- Developed a basic automated marketing system, including a contact database and three email templates aligned with the CHB brand.
- Integrated Google Analytics and Tag Manager into the site to track and analyze event conversion.
 - Yr/yr increase of 129% for form submissions

Director of Marketing

2021 - 2022

Davis Phinney Foundation

- Managed a team of three junior staff.
- Built and evaluated department goals and key performance indicators to increase engagement across web, email, paid media, nurture, direct mail, and events.
- Wrote content for web, email, social, PR, paid ads, and podcasts

Lead Digital Communications Manager

2020 - 2021

The Water Research Foundation

• Developed and managed multi-channel strategies to enhance WRF's AMS, CMS, CDN, and marketing platforms.



CHRISTOPHER HARRIS

Digital Marketing & Web Development

EDUCATION

2023 - Bootcamp Full Stack Coding Bootacmp University of Denver

2021 - Certificate

Management Essentials Harvard Business School Online

2016 - Master's Degree

Organizational Communication Speciality: Web Design & Development University of Denver

2011 - Bachelor's Degree

Business Champlain College

SKILLS

Website Development
HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL, Python
Content Marketing
Email Marketing
Social Media
Print Design
SEO/SEM
Database Management
Google Analytics, Tag Manager, and
Looker

Agile/SCRUM Project Management

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

- Created and served personalization campaigns to targeted user segments using behavioral and demographic data
 - 8.07% increase in wildfire research downloads
 - 67.51% increase in webinar registrations
- Managed the development and success of all digital channels, including the website, social media, email, webcasts, digital publications, SEO, and display advertising
 - 5,887.40% increase in new subscriber accounts created
 - 15,046.90% increase in subscriber content downloads

Digital Communications Manager

2017 - 2020

The Water Research Foundation

- Managed a team of five tasked with integrating two association management databases; developing a new UI/UX, IA, and content taxonomy; and designing, testing, and launching a brand-new website on Drupal
- Overhauled the email marketing platform by building five new email templates that increased delivery rates between 18-20%, open rates between 5-7%, and click-through rates between 2-6%
- Designed and managed the Foundation's social media strategy, which led to an increase in followers of 116.34% on Twitter, 721.91% on LinkedIn, 293.80% on Facebook, and 844.17% on Instagram
- Built the data reporting structure in Google Data Studio for all marketing platforms

Enrollment Marketing & Communications Specialist 2014 - 2017 Colorado School of Public Health

- Designed and executed the first multi-channel recruitment marketing plan with a budget of \$34,000, including print and email marketing, search and display advertising, social media, and retargeting campaigns. The implementation led to a 102% increase in inquiry generation
- Co-managed the development of the ColoradoSPH website, including a complete overhaul of the information architecture
 - 86.74% increase in organic traffic
 - 12.34% increase in paid traffic
 - 4.01% increase in registrations for Zoom information sessions
- Designed, wrote, distributed, and managed all current and prospective communications
- Wrote op-eds and blog posts highlighting the achievements of the students, faculty, and staff